Zack, Arnold Arbitration Files 5281
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Arnold Zack Arbitration Files
1980-1984
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Zack, Arnold
5281
5 cubic feet
5 linear ft.
Arbitration decisions, correspondence.
Files of the arbitrator Arnold Zack.
5621936
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, September 24, 2013
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, March 11, 2015
Biographical / Historical
Lawyer, arbitrator, and government official; LLB Yale, 1956, MBA Harvard, 1961, MA Harvard, 1963.
Arnold Marshall Zack is an arbitrator and mediator. Beginning his labor career as a part-time election examiner for the National Labor Relations Board and as a case analyst for the U.S. Wage Stabilization Board (1950-1953), he was also a lecturer in labor economics at Simmons College, Northeastern University (1957-1963); an assistant to Saul Wallen, arbitrator, (1956-1960); director of the Labor-Management Institute of the American Academy of Arbitrators (1966-1968); and has served in various labor-related international posts for the United States government.
Other governmental service includes membership on panels for the Federal Mediation and Conciliation Service, the Massachusetts Public Employment Relations Board, the New York State Public Employment Relations Board, The New Jersey Public Employment Relations Board, The New York City Office of Collective Bargaining, and The National Mediation Board. Zack is also a panel member of the American Arbitration Association, and has served as the permanent arbitrator for a number of major corporations and unions and for the State of New York and the U.S. Postal Service.
Scope and Contents
Files of the arbitrator Arnold Zack.
Collection includes records from: Boston-Edison-Cranston, S.C.; Denver Public Education Program; Hershey Chocolate Co.; ITT Grinnell-Pueblo, Colorado; Rhode Island, State of-Yardney Electric Corp.; Maine, State of vs. Maine State Employees Assoc.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5512: Arnold Zack Arbitration Files 5551: Arnold M. Zack Additional Arbitration Files 5620: Arnold Zack Additional Arbitration Files 5659: Arnold Zack Additional Arbitration Files 5727: Arnold Zack Additional Arbitration Files
Arbitration, Industrial -- United States; Zack, Arnold
5621936
- Boston Edison - Cranston, S.C.. (Box 1)
  - Boston Edison/UWUA Local 369 Feb 13 1983 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Boston School Committee/Boston Teachers Union Mediation 1983 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Boston University/UAW Dist. 65 April 27 1983 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Bristol School Committee/Auxilliary School Personnel. Aug 9 1983 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Brockton School Committee/School Police Dec 21 1983 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Carol Cable Co./USWA June 9, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Colorado Springs/Teachers' Association April 4, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Colorado Springs Nov 13-15 1983 Mediation (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - State of Connecticut/State Vocational Federation Of Teachers Hartford May 23, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - State of Connecticut./CSEA Folder 1 Hartford 1983 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - State of Connecticut/CSEA 10/83 folder 2 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - State of Connecticut/Connecticut State Employees Association/Pension Coordinating Committee Exhibits 2+3 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - State of Connecticut/CSEA/Pension coordination Comm. Brief Exhibits (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - State of Connecticut/Connecticut State Employees Association. Judicial Inspector Folder 1 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - State of Connecticut/Connecticut State Employees Association. Judicial Inspector Folder 2 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - State of Connecticut./ Connecticut State Employees Association. 1983 Exhibits 16-23 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Exhibits 24-45 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Exhibits 46-61 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Cranston School Committee. Biltmore, Prov. Jan 10, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Denver Public Education Program - Hershey Chocolate Company. (Box 2)
  - DODDS/Overseas Federation Teachers Verona, Italy: Lee Disch Sept 28, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Denver Public Education Program/AAA SPEECH May 19, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Filene's/Local 1445 Jan 31, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Filene's/Food & Commercial Workers. 1130-2505-82, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Fleet Service/Teamsters #559 Hartford Nov 21, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Foster-Gloucester Regional School Committee. Nov 7, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Frontier Airlines/AFA Discharge, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Frontier Airlines/ALPA Denver, CO (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Frontier Airlines/Airline Pilots Association International, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - General Dynamics/UMSWA Local 5 Gr. No. 357A Oct 24, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - General Dynamics Corp./TUMSWA Nov 23, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Globe Security Local 540 Sept 19, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Goffstown, N.H. School Board. Mediation Feb, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Golden Nugget/Local 54 Sept 6, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Greyhound/ATU, Division 1210 Philadelphia. Discharge. (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Greyhound/ATU Jan 5, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Greyhound (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Harvard University/Local 26 June 14, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Hershey Foods Co./B & CW, 464v Hershey, PA, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Hershey Chocolate Local 464 June 24, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- ITT Grinnell - Pueblo, Colorado. (Box 3)
  - ITT Grinnell/Molders, Local 376 Phila. (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Johns Hopkins / 1199 E (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Lexington Education Association. Sept 22, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Long Island University/Local 3998 AAA NY Sept 15, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - State of Maine/MSEA (Augusta) Oct 19, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - MSAD #27/Maine Teachers Association Fort Kent Maine (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Manchester NH and Teachers (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Massachusetts Federation of Teachers/SEIU 495 June 7, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Massachusetts Federation of Teachers, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Massachusetts Turnpike Auth./Local 127 Nov 22, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Northeast Utilities/IBEW Nuclear Sirens Case, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Northwest/BRAC Jan, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - NWA/BRAC Sebree Case (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Philadelphia School Committee / Philadelphia Federation of Teachers (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Philadelphia School Committee / Philadelphia Federation of Teachers (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Procter & Gamble/Chemical Workers. Boston, MA (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - City of Providence/Local 1033 Oct 4, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Pueblo, Colorado (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Rhode Island, State of -Yardney Electric Corp.. (Box 4)
  - State of R.I./AFSCME greivance. April 5, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Rochester Telephone/C.W.A Rochester, NY Sept 20-21, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Rochester Telephone/CWA, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - S.P.I.D.R. Program Philadelphia, PA Oct. 7, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Scituate School Committee/MTA Fact Finding Oct 12, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - TWA/IAM Discharge (JFK) AAA Office, NYC June 29, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - USPS/APWA Boston, MA, Jan 14, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - USPS/APWU Boston, Mass. Jan 14, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - USPS/APWU Greivance. Holyoke Feb 10, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - USPS/APWU Holyoke, MA Feb 10, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - USPS/NALC New York City Jan 13, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - USPS/APWU NYC March 25, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - USPS/APWU NYC Greivance. March 11, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - USPS/APWU Boston, MA March 22, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - USPS/NALC Boston, MA May 6, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - USPS/NALC Boston, MA May 12, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - USPS/NALC Pitcher & Boston, MA March 28, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - USPS/NALC Class Action Case Hartford, CT July 20, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - USPS/APWU Class Action Worcester, MA June 3, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - USPS/NALC Hartford, CT Oct 13, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - USPS/NALC Boston, MA Oct 21, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - USPS/APWU NYC Nov 4, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - USPS/NBALC (4 cases) New Britain, CT Nov 10, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - USPS/NALC Springfield, MA Nov 18, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - USPS/NALC New York City Nov 25, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - USPS/Mailhandles greivance. Boston, MA Nov 30, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - USPS/APWU Dec 02, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - USPS/APWU Manchester, NH Oct 28, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - USPS/APWU (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - USPS/APWU Dec 8, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - USPS/APWU 5 Cases Hartford, CT Dec 12, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Yale Univ./Local 35 New Haven, CT June 21, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Yardney Electric Corp. July 7, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Yardney Electric. Greivance. Pawcatuck, CT Feb 16, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 34)
- Maine, State of vs. Maine State Employees Association. (Box 5)
  - Maine Arbitration - Live (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Maine, State of/Maine State Employees Association. 1982-1983 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - State of Maine - Sprayer's Guide, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - State of Maine/ Maine State Employees Association (MSEA), 1984 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Maine/MSEA, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Maine/MSEA, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - State's Presentation on Wages (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Union Exhibits (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - State Exhibits (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - State of Maine/MSEA Fact-Finding Report Sept 14, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Maine/MSEA July 7, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Maine/MSEA Oct 14, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Maine/MSEA, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Maine/MSEA, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 14)